<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>student unions on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/tags/student-unions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in student unions on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/tags/student-unions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importance of opting-in to student union levies</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</guid>
      <description>[Download the flyer here](/pdfs/OUWCC Handbill_ENG_Final_No crop.pdf)
What do we stand to lose under the student choice initiative? Vital services that benefit all those who work and study on campus, particularly marginalized communities.
Student unions’ and labour unions’ ability to represent and advocate for their members.
Many full-time paid opportunities at a living wage for workers.
Avenues for students and workers to hold campus administration and government accountable.
A strong and united movement between students and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts about Ford&#39;s cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/cutsfacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/cutsfacts/</guid>
      <description>An overview of Ontario government&amp;rsquo;s cuts to higher education and the attempted bankrupting of democratic student organizations.
More information pages from our coalition partners available here.
Summary Unfunded 10% Tuition Fee Reduction will result in an approximate 4% cut to university budgets. Universities will be under pressure to outsource, cut services, increase precarious employment, and/or lay-off staff.
Regressive OSAP changes will result in massive increased student debt and increased burden for mature students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court Strikes Down Ford&#39;s Student Choice Initiative</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-victory/</guid>
      <description>Students declare victory in lawsuit against Ford&amp;rsquo;s attempt to defund them Link to PDF of decision
The Canadian Federation of Students, the York Federation of Students and Goldblatt Partners held a joint press conference Friday morning, November 11, 2019, to respond to the Ontario Divisional Court’s unanimous decision to quash the Ford government’s “Student Choice Initiative”.
&amp;ldquo;Today the Ontario Divisional Court has confirmed what students already knew: The Student Choice Initiative is unlawful, and the Ford government acted beyond their authority.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
