<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ford&#39;s Cuts to PSE and how to fight on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ford&#39;s Cuts to PSE and how to fight on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/ford/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importance of opting-in to student union levies</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</guid>
      <description>[Download the flyer here](/pdfs/OUWCC Handbill_ENG_Final_No crop.pdf)
What do we stand to lose under the student choice initiative? Vital services that benefit all those who work and study on campus, particularly marginalized communities.
Student unions’ and labour unions’ ability to represent and advocate for their members.
Many full-time paid opportunities at a living wage for workers.
Avenues for students and workers to hold campus administration and government accountable.
A strong and united movement between students and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts about Ford&#39;s cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/cutsfacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/cutsfacts/</guid>
      <description>An overview of Ontario government&amp;rsquo;s cuts to higher education and the attempted bankrupting of democratic student organizations.
More information pages from our coalition partners available here.
Summary Unfunded 10% Tuition Fee Reduction will result in an approximate 4% cut to university budgets. Universities will be under pressure to outsource, cut services, increase precarious employment, and/or lay-off staff.
Regressive OSAP changes will result in massive increased student debt and increased burden for mature students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking points on the cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/talkingpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/talkingpoints/</guid>
      <description>Overview Students and workers are appalled by the Doug Ford government’s shameful attempt to use a tuition fee reduction as a political gimmick to try and hide a $600 million cut to student grants, a $440 million cut to university and college budgets, all and a petty and vindictive attack on democratic students’ unions.
Ontario’s faculty, staff, and students are united in our opposition to these cuts and attacks, which threaten education quality, accessibility, and student life on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to coalition pages</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/coalitionlinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/coalitionlinks/</guid>
      <description>Many organizations are releasing specific membership advisories, annoucements, and explanations of what is going on. You will find a list of materials and organization-specific information linked below.
Unifor #WeAreTheStudents: Unite for Student Democracy and Against OSAP Cutbacks </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Yes! to campus life and student services</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/1281materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/1281materials/</guid>
      <description>Resources student unions provide Beginning this year, you have the option to opt-in, or out, of certain student fees. Here are just some of the many services that these fees pay for - and what you could potentially miss out on.
Be sure to support your student levy groups and access their services.
Download this flyer in PDF form here
Access to resources Did you know that many of the student levy groups on campus can provide you with access to resoures you may need?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways Ford Government’s Post Secondary Education Announcement is Bad for Students and their Families</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/10-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/10-ways/</guid>
      <description>Ten Negative Effects The Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities the following negative proposals can be confirmed:
International students, who pay the highest tuition fees, are ineligible for a 10% reduction in tuition fees. Universities and colleges will face funding cuts of up to $440 million which impact the quality of education in the province. These deep cuts are expected to be downloaded onto students and workers through larger class sizes, fewer course options and cuts to wages and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
