<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryerson on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campuses/ryerson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ryerson on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/campuses/ryerson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ryerson University Campus Coalition Meeting: Feb 13</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, February 13 4-6pm Venn (RCC 103). Contact the coalition at Ryerson at wearethestudentsRU@gmail.com.
Coalition Meeting Invitation We Are The Students Ryerson would like to invite you and your members to attend our upcoming coalition meeting. We are a group of students and community members that are concerned about the announced changes to OSAP and post-secondary funding as well as how student fees will be collected. We know that these changes will cause uncertain work conditions for staff and faculty, less access to education and lower the value of students’ education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are the Students Ryerson: Statement on Ford&#39;s Cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-statement/</guid>
      <description>How Ryerson students will be impacted On January 17th, the provincial government announced sweeping rollbacks to the Ontario Student Assistance Program (OSAP), funding for Ontario colleges and universities and dramatically altering how student fees are administered.
The provincial government has announced a 10 per cent cut to tuition fees for domestic students across all programs, which will adversely affect each institutions’ funding. The government has also rolled back OSAP regulations to their 2016 form, which will result in a reduction in non-repayable grants and an increase in student loans and, therefore, the amount of student debt, while also proposing to remove the 6-month grace period for charging interest on student loans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
