<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flyer on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/materials/flyer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flyer on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/materials/flyer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importance of opting-in to student union levies</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</guid>
      <description>[Download the flyer here](/pdfs/OUWCC Handbill_ENG_Final_No crop.pdf)
What do we stand to lose under the student choice initiative? Vital services that benefit all those who work and study on campus, particularly marginalized communities.
Student unions’ and labour unions’ ability to represent and advocate for their members.
Many full-time paid opportunities at a living wage for workers.
Avenues for students and workers to hold campus administration and government accountable.
A strong and united movement between students and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways Ford Government’s Post Secondary Education Announcement is Bad for Students and their Families</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/10-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/10-ways/</guid>
      <description>Ten Negative Effects The Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities the following negative proposals can be confirmed:
International students, who pay the highest tuition fees, are ineligible for a 10% reduction in tuition fees. Universities and colleges will face funding cuts of up to $440 million which impact the quality of education in the province. These deep cuts are expected to be downloaded onto students and workers through larger class sizes, fewer course options and cuts to wages and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
