<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test Title</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/testpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/testpage/</guid>
      <description>This is a test page. More of a test page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students and Workers Demand Safer return to campus</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-safe-return-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-safe-return-2022/</guid>
      <description>English Students and Workers Demand Safer return to campus Add your voice by sending the email below to the Ministry of Colleges and Universities and let&amp;rsquo;s keep fighting for Safer Campuses by signing:
Safer Return to Campus Email Zap! The Ontario University and Colleges Coalition echoes the concerns of students and workers across the province about unsafe and rushed plans to return to campus. With notice of returning back to in-person learning for some institutions as soon as January 31, students are nervous about inadequate safety plans, the accessibility of continuing with online learning and academic penalties for those who do not feel safe being back on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario university and college faculty, staff, and students give Ford government failing grade on plans for postsecondary education</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/performace-based-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/performace-based-funding/</guid>
      <description>The Ford government recently announced its plans to steamroll ahead with a reckless “performance” based funding plan. Postsecondary faculty, academic librarians, staff, and students are opposed to this flawed funding experiment and give the government a failing grade for its approach.
The government, which already provides the lowest postsecondary per-student funding in Canada, has now announced that it will allow per-student funding to drop by more than 10 per cent. This negligence will starve Ontario universities and colleges of vital resources required to ensure students receive a high-quality education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada Christian College should be denied university status (archived)</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/canada-christian-college-should-be-denied-university-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/canada-christian-college-should-be-denied-university-status/</guid>
      <description>In a letter to Minister of Colleges and Universities Ross Romano, the OUCC has raised concerns about the privatization of postsecondary education in Ontario and the government&amp;rsquo;s efforts to grant university status to the controversial Canada Christian College.
Hon. Ross Romano
Minister of Colleges and Universities
Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities
5th Floor, 438 University Ave
Toronto, ON M7A 2A5
ross.romano@pc.ola.org
November 2, 2020
Dear Minister Romano,
We write as representatives of the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition (OUCC)—which represents over 435,000 faculty, staff, and students from every public postsecondary institution in Ontario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End Contracting Out at University of Toronto</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/endcontracting-ut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/endcontracting-ut/</guid>
      <description>End Contracting Out
Update On August 17th, 2020 the University of Toronto initiated a new contracting out plan by privatizing a significant portion of caretaking services. The University removed and transferred CUPE 3261 caretakers from 18 buildings at the St. George Campus, replacing them with two private companies to provide cleaning services. These companies employ low-paid workers with little to no benefits.
As a &amp;ldquo;Top 10&amp;rdquo; Employer and a premier public institution, most would expect U of T to provide good job opportunities alongside high-quality cleaning services, especially during COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education for All</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ed-for-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ed-for-all/</guid>
      <description>The Canadian Federation of Students&amp;ndash;Ontario has launched a campaign called Education for All.
Access to post secondary education is a critical part of responding to the COVID-19 crisis and ensuring a successful social and economic recovery. Unfortunately, decades of government funding shortfalls have created barriers to accessing education. Ontario students pay some of the highest tuition fees in the country and graduate with an average $28,000 in debt.
Click the image below to learn more about the campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OSAP “information module” does nothing to address financial barriers to post-secondary education | CFS Ontario</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/osapmodule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/osapmodule/</guid>
      <description>Originally published by the CFS Ontario
Ontario Student Assistance Program (OSAP) applications for the 2020-2021 academic year opened on May 20. The application now requires students to complete a mandatory “information module” that purports to highlight financial literacy. Students are disappointed in this addition to the OSAP application process, which is both patronizing and does not address the true financial barriers to post-secondary education.
“Students face barriers repaying student debt because of the high cost of education, not because of a lack of financial literacy,” said Kayla Weiler, Ontario Representative of the Canadian Federation of Students, “what students really need is more grants instead of loans, and greater public investment into post-secondary education to reduce and ultimately eliminate tuition fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate students supports needed during COVID-19 crisis</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/grad-students-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/grad-students-covid/</guid>
      <description>Addressed to Federal Government, Provincial Governments, Canada’s Research Funding Councils, and University senior administrators:
The COVID-19 pandemic has posed unprecedented challenges to graduate students across the country. We recognize the steps taken by both the federal and provincial governments, and post-secondary institutions, to protect not just graduate students, but all students, faculty, and staff. These measures include the six-month suspension of student loan repayment and the expansion of the Canada Summer Jobs program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract Instructors at Carleton University vote 92.5% in favour of strike action, if necessary</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-4600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-4600/</guid>
      <description>OTTAWA, ON - Contract Instructors (CIs) at Carleton University, represented by Unit 2, Local 4600 of the Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE 4600-2), have voted overwhelmingly this week to authorize job action if necessary to secure a fair deal at the bargaining table.
The Union has been negotiating with Carleton since last summer, but several major issues remain unresolved. The union has also requested the assistance of a Ministry of Labour conciliation officer to help move discussions forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario universities must respect the autonomy of students’ unions</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/studentunion-autonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/studentunion-autonomy/</guid>
      <description>Students’ unions, founded by and for students, are fully autonomous organizations governed by democratically elected boards and executives. They are membership-driven organizations funded by their members through dues.
University administrations do not have the authority and cannot justify violating the legal autonomy of students’ unions or any other campus unions.
Regardless of their motives for doing so, university administrations have no right to:
withhold students’ union membership dues; interfere in students’ union elections or operations; or attempt to shut down students’ unions (or any other legally autonomous organization).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court Strikes Down Ford&#39;s Student Choice Initiative</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-victory/</guid>
      <description>Students declare victory in lawsuit against Ford&amp;rsquo;s attempt to defund them Link to PDF of decision
The Canadian Federation of Students, the York Federation of Students and Goldblatt Partners held a joint press conference Friday morning, November 11, 2019, to respond to the Ontario Divisional Court’s unanimous decision to quash the Ford government’s “Student Choice Initiative”.
&amp;ldquo;Today the Ontario Divisional Court has confirmed what students already knew: The Student Choice Initiative is unlawful, and the Ford government acted beyond their authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ford&#39;s attack on public sector workers&#39; compensation includes university and college workers</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/compensationcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/compensationcut/</guid>
      <description>The Ford government has introduced legislation to cap increases in total compensation at an average (benefits and wages) of 1% per year for all public sector employees, including university and college workers. The legislation will affect all collective agreements on expiry and last three years. Current bargaining will continue, but while the bill has not passed yet, it&amp;rsquo;s current language says it will apply retroactively to June 5, 2019.
Government attack on workers’ rights will deny fair wages and benefits to contract faculty and already underpaid academic staff | OCUFA Ontario faculty are deeply concerned by the Ford government’s attempt to cap public sector compensation increases at one per cent per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Federation of Students and York Federation of Students file legal challenge against Ontario Government’s Student Choice Initiative</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/response-studentchoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/response-studentchoice/</guid>
      <description>Toronto, ON – The Canadian Federation of Students and the York Federation of Students have jointly filed a legal challenge against the Government of Ontario’s Student Choice Initiative, on the basis that the government lacked the authority to implement such a policy and acted with improper purpose.
“This policy is a direct attack on students’ ability to organize and provide essential services on campus,” said Sofia Descalzi, incoming chairperson of the Canadian Federation of Students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are the Students Ryerson: Statement on Ford&#39;s Cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-statement/</guid>
      <description>How Ryerson students will be impacted On January 17th, the provincial government announced sweeping rollbacks to the Ontario Student Assistance Program (OSAP), funding for Ontario colleges and universities and dramatically altering how student fees are administered.
The provincial government has announced a 10 per cent cut to tuition fees for domestic students across all programs, which will adversely affect each institutions’ funding. The government has also rolled back OSAP regulations to their 2016 form, which will result in a reduction in non-repayable grants and an increase in student loans and, therefore, the amount of student debt, while also proposing to remove the 6-month grace period for charging interest on student loans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United against Ford government’s reckless attacks on postsecondary education and students</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/fordscuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/fordscuts/</guid>
      <description>Cuts to higher education will be devastating to students, workers, and research Students and workers are appalled by the Doug Ford government’s shameful attempt to use a tuition fee reduction as a political gimmick to try and hide a $600 million cut to student grants, a $440 million cut to university and college budgets, all and a petty and vindictive attack on democratic students’ unions.
Ontario’s faculty, staff, and students are united in our opposition to these cuts and attacks, which threaten education quality, accessibility, and student life on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on government-mandated free speech policies</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/freespeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/freespeech/</guid>
      <description>Ontario’s universities and colleges are vital spaces where a culture of rich academic debate and free expression should be fostered. Core to the mandate of our postsecondary institutions is the advancement of knowledge, and that requires our campuses to be places where all community members have the right to speak their minds and respectfully challenge each other intellectually. Faculty associations, labour unions, and student unions deeply believe in these rights, and will continue our collective work to uphold them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
