<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test Title</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/testpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/testpage/</guid>
      <description>This is a test page. More of a test page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students and Workers Demand Safer return to campus</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-safe-return-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-safe-return-2022/</guid>
      <description>English Students and Workers Demand Safer return to campus Add your voice by sending the email below to the Ministry of Colleges and Universities and let&amp;rsquo;s keep fighting for Safer Campuses by signing:
Safer Return to Campus Email Zap! The Ontario University and Colleges Coalition echoes the concerns of students and workers across the province about unsafe and rushed plans to return to campus. With notice of returning back to in-person learning for some institutions as soon as January 31, students are nervous about inadequate safety plans, the accessibility of continuing with online learning and academic penalties for those who do not feel safe being back on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario university and college faculty, staff, and students give Ford government failing grade on plans for postsecondary education</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/performace-based-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/performace-based-funding/</guid>
      <description>The Ford government recently announced its plans to steamroll ahead with a reckless “performance” based funding plan. Postsecondary faculty, academic librarians, staff, and students are opposed to this flawed funding experiment and give the government a failing grade for its approach.
The government, which already provides the lowest postsecondary per-student funding in Canada, has now announced that it will allow per-student funding to drop by more than 10 per cent. This negligence will starve Ontario universities and colleges of vital resources required to ensure students receive a high-quality education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada Christian College should be denied university status (archived)</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/canada-christian-college-should-be-denied-university-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/canada-christian-college-should-be-denied-university-status/</guid>
      <description>In a letter to Minister of Colleges and Universities Ross Romano, the OUCC has raised concerns about the privatization of postsecondary education in Ontario and the government&amp;rsquo;s efforts to grant university status to the controversial Canada Christian College.
Hon. Ross Romano
Minister of Colleges and Universities
Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities
5th Floor, 438 University Ave
Toronto, ON M7A 2A5
ross.romano@pc.ola.org
November 2, 2020
Dear Minister Romano,
We write as representatives of the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition (OUCC)—which represents over 435,000 faculty, staff, and students from every public postsecondary institution in Ontario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education for All</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ed-for-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ed-for-all/</guid>
      <description>The Canadian Federation of Students&amp;ndash;Ontario has launched a campaign called Education for All.
Access to post secondary education is a critical part of responding to the COVID-19 crisis and ensuring a successful social and economic recovery. Unfortunately, decades of government funding shortfalls have created barriers to accessing education. Ontario students pay some of the highest tuition fees in the country and graduate with an average $28,000 in debt.
Click the image below to learn more about the campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OSAP “information module” does nothing to address financial barriers to post-secondary education | CFS Ontario</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/osapmodule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/osapmodule/</guid>
      <description>Originally published by the CFS Ontario
Ontario Student Assistance Program (OSAP) applications for the 2020-2021 academic year opened on May 20. The application now requires students to complete a mandatory “information module” that purports to highlight financial literacy. Students are disappointed in this addition to the OSAP application process, which is both patronizing and does not address the true financial barriers to post-secondary education.
“Students face barriers repaying student debt because of the high cost of education, not because of a lack of financial literacy,” said Kayla Weiler, Ontario Representative of the Canadian Federation of Students, “what students really need is more grants instead of loans, and greater public investment into post-secondary education to reduce and ultimately eliminate tuition fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate students supports needed during COVID-19 crisis</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/grad-students-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/grad-students-covid/</guid>
      <description>Addressed to Federal Government, Provincial Governments, Canada’s Research Funding Councils, and University senior administrators:
The COVID-19 pandemic has posed unprecedented challenges to graduate students across the country. We recognize the steps taken by both the federal and provincial governments, and post-secondary institutions, to protect not just graduate students, but all students, faculty, and staff. These measures include the six-month suspension of student loan repayment and the expansion of the Canada Summer Jobs program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario universities must respect the autonomy of students’ unions</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/studentunion-autonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/studentunion-autonomy/</guid>
      <description>Students’ unions, founded by and for students, are fully autonomous organizations governed by democratically elected boards and executives. They are membership-driven organizations funded by their members through dues.
University administrations do not have the authority and cannot justify violating the legal autonomy of students’ unions or any other campus unions.
Regardless of their motives for doing so, university administrations have no right to:
withhold students’ union membership dues; interfere in students’ union elections or operations; or attempt to shut down students’ unions (or any other legally autonomous organization).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court Strikes Down Ford&#39;s Student Choice Initiative</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-victory/</guid>
      <description>Students declare victory in lawsuit against Ford&amp;rsquo;s attempt to defund them Link to PDF of decision
The Canadian Federation of Students, the York Federation of Students and Goldblatt Partners held a joint press conference Friday morning, November 11, 2019, to respond to the Ontario Divisional Court’s unanimous decision to quash the Ford government’s “Student Choice Initiative”.
&amp;ldquo;Today the Ontario Divisional Court has confirmed what students already knew: The Student Choice Initiative is unlawful, and the Ford government acted beyond their authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ford&#39;s attack on public sector workers&#39; compensation includes university and college workers</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/compensationcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/compensationcut/</guid>
      <description>The Ford government has introduced legislation to cap increases in total compensation at an average (benefits and wages) of 1% per year for all public sector employees, including university and college workers. The legislation will affect all collective agreements on expiry and last three years. Current bargaining will continue, but while the bill has not passed yet, it&amp;rsquo;s current language says it will apply retroactively to June 5, 2019.
Government attack on workers’ rights will deny fair wages and benefits to contract faculty and already underpaid academic staff | OCUFA Ontario faculty are deeply concerned by the Ford government’s attempt to cap public sector compensation increases at one per cent per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Federation of Students and York Federation of Students file legal challenge against Ontario Government’s Student Choice Initiative</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/response-studentchoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/response-studentchoice/</guid>
      <description>Toronto, ON – The Canadian Federation of Students and the York Federation of Students have jointly filed a legal challenge against the Government of Ontario’s Student Choice Initiative, on the basis that the government lacked the authority to implement such a policy and acted with improper purpose.
“This policy is a direct attack on students’ ability to organize and provide essential services on campus,” said Sofia Descalzi, incoming chairperson of the Canadian Federation of Students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United against Ford government’s reckless attacks on postsecondary education and students</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/fordscuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/fordscuts/</guid>
      <description>Cuts to higher education will be devastating to students, workers, and research Students and workers are appalled by the Doug Ford government’s shameful attempt to use a tuition fee reduction as a political gimmick to try and hide a $600 million cut to student grants, a $440 million cut to university and college budgets, all and a petty and vindictive attack on democratic students’ unions.
Ontario’s faculty, staff, and students are united in our opposition to these cuts and attacks, which threaten education quality, accessibility, and student life on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on government-mandated free speech policies</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/freespeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/freespeech/</guid>
      <description>Ontario’s universities and colleges are vital spaces where a culture of rich academic debate and free expression should be fostered. Core to the mandate of our postsecondary institutions is the advancement of knowledge, and that requires our campuses to be places where all community members have the right to speak their minds and respectfully challenge each other intellectually. Faculty associations, labour unions, and student unions deeply believe in these rights, and will continue our collective work to uphold them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/from-across-ontario-faculty-students-and-staff-call-on-ross-romano-to-provide-more-funding-for-laurentian-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/from-across-ontario-faculty-students-and-staff-call-on-ross-romano-to-provide-more-funding-for-laurentian-university/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2021-03-01T05:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;Members of the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition (OUCC), which represents over 435,000 faculty, staff, and students from every public postsecondary education institution in Ontario, are calling on Ross Romano and the Ontario government to provide Laurentian University with the necessary funding to secure the future of the university.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; thumbnail = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; title = &amp;ldquo;From across Ontario, faculty, students, and staff call on Ross Romano to provide more funding for Laurentian University&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/june-7-8-days-of-action-resist-ford-cuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/june-7-8-days-of-action-resist-ford-cuts/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;All&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Events&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-05-25T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;June 7 marks one year of resisting government cuts to public services, education, health care and decent work. We will be hitting the streets across Ontario to show that we didn&amp;rsquo;t vote for that. Join an action in a community near you! Actions are being organized right now for EITHER June 7 or June 8. RSVP here and we will send you details of the actions in your area for you to take part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ocufa-estimates-ford-s-performance-funding-could-cut-university-budgets-by-over-500-million-dollars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ocufa-estimates-ford-s-performance-funding-could-cut-university-budgets-by-over-500-million-dollars/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-09-04T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Ontario faculty are warning that the Ford government’s so called “performance” funding model for postsecondary education is reckless, ineffective, and dangerous. The new funding model will link 60 per cent of government funding for universities ($2.2 billion dollars) to an arbitrary set of metrics chosen with no consultation. These metrics will not actually measure “performance” but are likely to be used as an excuse to cut university budgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ontario-faculty-staff-and-students-oppose-ford-government-s-performance-funding-for-postsecondary-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ontario-faculty-staff-and-students-oppose-ford-government-s-performance-funding-for-postsecondary-institutions/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-09-05T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Announced in the Ontario Budget, the Ford government’s reckless new market-based approach to funding postsecondary education will fundamentally compromise the integrity of Ontario’s higher education system. This alarming shift in education funding will create greater inequity, hurt students, and threaten the quality of education in our province.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;performance-funding&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/bitmap2.png&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Ontario faculty, staff, and students oppose Ford government’s “performance” funding for postsecondary institutions&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ontario-s-postsecondary-staff-students-and-faculty-support-paid-sick-days-for-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/ontario-s-postsecondary-staff-students-and-faculty-support-paid-sick-days-for-all/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2021-02-11T05:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;Members of the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition (OUCC), which represents over 435,000 faculty, staff, and students from every public postsecondary education institution in Ontario, support the Decent Work and Health Network’s call for seven (7) permanent, paid sick days for all workers and an additional fourteen (14) paid sick days during public health outbreaks. &amp;quot; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/eps2nttw8aaei1s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-opposes-bill-307-and-ford-s-attempt-to-silence-workers-and-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-opposes-bill-307-and-ford-s-attempt-to-silence-workers-and-students/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2021-07-21T04:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;Far too often, information around post-secondary education issues are lost during large election campaigns broadly focused on winning votes, not necessarily addressing the challenges facing our public post-secondary education system. The imposition of Bill 307 does not remedy this issue. Rather, it hinders the ability of students’ unions, labour unions, and other independent democratic organizations to educate their members and the public on the nature of provincial elections, democracy, and the importance of their participation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-sends-letter-of-solidarity-for-striking-support-workers-at-university-of-ottawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-sends-letter-of-solidarity-for-striking-support-workers-at-university-of-ottawa/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2020-10-19T04:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;We are writing to express our support for PSUO-SSOU, the certified Bargaining Unit for 1,300 administrative and support staff at the University of Ottawa. We are deeply concerned that your administration is trying to strip the health benefits of these workers during the pandemic as they work tirelessly to keep the university running during these unprecedented times.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/122115597_399937854725009_8398704238997636820_n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-statement-on-july-29-day-of-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/oucc-statement-on-july-29-day-of-action/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2020-07-28T04:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;Members of the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition (OUCC), which represents over 435,000 faculty, staff, and students from every public postsecondary institution in Ontario, stand in solidarity with students, educators, and parents in their demand for adequate public funding to allow for a safe reopening of schools in September.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/ed5drevwaaaugfy.jpeg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;OUCC statement on July 29 Day of Action for a #SafeSeptember&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-walk-out-at-noon-on-march-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/student-walk-out-at-noon-on-march-20/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Events&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-04T17:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Join students from across the province in a walk out on Wednesday March 20 at 12 pm to demonstrate to the Ontario government that we will not tolerate their attacks on students.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;studentwalkout&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/walkout.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Student Walkout at Noon on March 20&amp;rdquo;
+++
Province Wide Student Walkout Wednesday, March 20 12 pm (noon) Add to calendar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/students-faculty-and-staff-raise-concerns-about-use-of-invasive-proctoring-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/students-faculty-and-staff-raise-concerns-about-use-of-invasive-proctoring-software/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2020-07-02T04:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;Today, the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition sent the following letter to Minister of Colleges and Universities Ross Romano raising concerns about the use of invasive proctoring software.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/lianhao-qu-lfan1gswv5c-unsplash.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Students, faculty, and staff raise concerns about use of invasive proctoring software&amp;rdquo;
+++ Today, the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition sent the following letter to Minister of Colleges and Universities Ross Romano and Minister of Labour, Training and Skills Development Monte McNaughton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/post/unions-and-joint-health-and-safety-committees-must-be-part-of-planning-for-return-to-campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/post/unions-and-joint-health-and-safety-committees-must-be-part-of-planning-for-return-to-campus/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [] categories = [&amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;] date = 2020-05-26T04:00:00Z description = &amp;ldquo;Today, the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition sent the following letter to Minister of Colleges and Universities Ross Romano and Minister of Labour, Training and Skills Development Monte McNaughton.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/claudio-schwarz-purzlbaum-l8ipde99z9c-unsplash.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Unions and Joint Health and Safety Committees must be involved in planning for return to campus&amp;rdquo;
+++ Today, the Ontario Universities and Colleges Coalition sent the following letter to Minister of Colleges and Universities Ross Romano and Minister of Labour, Training and Skills Development Monte McNaughton.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
