<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Local Actions on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/categories/local-actions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Local Actions on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/categories/local-actions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End Contracting Out at University of Toronto</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/endcontracting-ut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/endcontracting-ut/</guid>
      <description>End Contracting Out
Update On August 17th, 2020 the University of Toronto initiated a new contracting out plan by privatizing a significant portion of caretaking services. The University removed and transferred CUPE 3261 caretakers from 18 buildings at the St. George Campus, replacing them with two private companies to provide cleaning services. These companies employ low-paid workers with little to no benefits.
As a &amp;ldquo;Top 10&amp;rdquo; Employer and a premier public institution, most would expect U of T to provide good job opportunities alongside high-quality cleaning services, especially during COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banner Drop at McMaster University</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/mac-banner-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/mac-banner-drop/</guid>
      <description>CUPE 3906 is currently in bargaining for their Teaching Assistants and Post-Doctoral Fellows at McMaster University. The CUPE local is attempting to challenge Bill 124 and restrictions on wage increases.
The local is getting ready to increase mobilizations for the new school year. The direct action and education outreach focused on how Bill 124 and cuts to post-secondary are impacting students and workers at McMaster University. Banners were targeted at the university&amp;rsquo;s compliance in the Ford government&amp;rsquo;s attacks on students and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilfrid Laurier Brantford Campus Walkout: March 20th at Noon</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/wilfrid-laurier-brantford-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/wilfrid-laurier-brantford-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>Join Students Against Ford Cuts and others at the Wilfrid Laurier University &amp;ndash; Brantford Campus in a peaceful protest of the OSAP cuts and, so-called, student choice initiative.
Rally and speakers in the
March 20 12pm-1pm David Fuels Walkway Facebook event Show your support by pinning a red square to your clothes!
Speakers TBA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest at MPP Jeff Yurek&#39;s office: March 8 @ 11:30am</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/london-march8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/london-march8/</guid>
      <description>You are invited to a protest with the London Student Coalition and labour allies this Friday at the office of Elgin-Middlesex-London PC MPP Jeff Yurek.
Buses from Fanshawe and Western and onsite pizza will be provided by OPSEU from the Fight Ford Fund.
Friday, March 8 11:30am 750 Talbot Street, St. Thomas Facebook event information Catch the Bus From Western University The free bus to the rally leaves from:
Middlesex College circle 11am Catch the Bus from Fanshawe The free bus to the rally leaves from:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trent University Walkout: March 20 at Noon</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/trent-march20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/trent-march20/</guid>
      <description>The Peterborough Coalition Against Cuts to Education invites you to a cross-campus walkout in solidarity with students across Ontario to protest the cuts to post secondary education.
March 20 12 pm (noon) Bata Podium Add to Calendar
Peterborough Coalition Against Cuts to Education is organizing a walkout on March 20 at noon in solidarity with students across Ontario. In solidarity with students, campus unions TUFA and CUPE will be supportive of students leaving class for this event.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
