<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talking points on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/categories/talking-points/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talking points on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/categories/talking-points/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importance of opting-in to student union levies</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/optincupe/</guid>
      <description>[Download the flyer here](/pdfs/OUWCC Handbill_ENG_Final_No crop.pdf)
What do we stand to lose under the student choice initiative? Vital services that benefit all those who work and study on campus, particularly marginalized communities.
Student unions’ and labour unions’ ability to represent and advocate for their members.
Many full-time paid opportunities at a living wage for workers.
Avenues for students and workers to hold campus administration and government accountable.
A strong and united movement between students and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking points on the cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/talkingpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/ford/talkingpoints/</guid>
      <description>Overview Students and workers are appalled by the Doug Ford government’s shameful attempt to use a tuition fee reduction as a political gimmick to try and hide a $600 million cut to student grants, a $440 million cut to university and college budgets, all and a petty and vindictive attack on democratic students’ unions.
Ontario’s faculty, staff, and students are united in our opposition to these cuts and attacks, which threaten education quality, accessibility, and student life on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
