<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Local Campus Coalition Organizing on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</title>
    <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Local Campus Coalition Organizing on Ontario Universities &amp; Colleges Coalition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://campuscoalition.org/campus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End Contracting Out at University of Toronto</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/endcontracting-ut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/endcontracting-ut/</guid>
      <description>End Contracting Out
Update On August 17th, 2020 the University of Toronto initiated a new contracting out plan by privatizing a significant portion of caretaking services. The University removed and transferred CUPE 3261 caretakers from 18 buildings at the St. George Campus, replacing them with two private companies to provide cleaning services. These companies employ low-paid workers with little to no benefits.
As a &amp;ldquo;Top 10&amp;rdquo; Employer and a premier public institution, most would expect U of T to provide good job opportunities alongside high-quality cleaning services, especially during COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract Instructors at Carleton University vote 92.5% in favour of strike action, if necessary</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-4600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-4600/</guid>
      <description>OTTAWA, ON - Contract Instructors (CIs) at Carleton University, represented by Unit 2, Local 4600 of the Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE 4600-2), have voted overwhelmingly this week to authorize job action if necessary to secure a fair deal at the bargaining table.
The Union has been negotiating with Carleton since last summer, but several major issues remain unresolved. The union has also requested the assistance of a Ministry of Labour conciliation officer to help move discussions forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banner Drop at McMaster University</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/mac-banner-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/mac-banner-drop/</guid>
      <description>CUPE 3906 is currently in bargaining for their Teaching Assistants and Post-Doctoral Fellows at McMaster University. The CUPE local is attempting to challenge Bill 124 and restrictions on wage increases.
The local is getting ready to increase mobilizations for the new school year. The direct action and education outreach focused on how Bill 124 and cuts to post-secondary are impacting students and workers at McMaster University. Banners were targeted at the university&amp;rsquo;s compliance in the Ford government&amp;rsquo;s attacks on students and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilfrid Laurier Brantford Campus Walkout: March 20th at Noon</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/wilfrid-laurier-brantford-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/wilfrid-laurier-brantford-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>Join Students Against Ford Cuts and others at the Wilfrid Laurier University &amp;ndash; Brantford Campus in a peaceful protest of the OSAP cuts and, so-called, student choice initiative.
Rally and speakers in the
March 20 12pm-1pm David Fuels Walkway Facebook event Show your support by pinning a red square to your clothes!
Speakers TBA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest at MPP Jeff Yurek&#39;s office: March 8 @ 11:30am</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/london-march8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/london-march8/</guid>
      <description>You are invited to a protest with the London Student Coalition and labour allies this Friday at the office of Elgin-Middlesex-London PC MPP Jeff Yurek.
Buses from Fanshawe and Western and onsite pizza will be provided by OPSEU from the Fight Ford Fund.
Friday, March 8 11:30am 750 Talbot Street, St. Thomas Facebook event information Catch the Bus From Western University The free bus to the rally leaves from:
Middlesex College circle 11am Catch the Bus from Fanshawe The free bus to the rally leaves from:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trent University Walkout: March 20 at Noon</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/trent-march20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/trent-march20/</guid>
      <description>The Peterborough Coalition Against Cuts to Education invites you to a cross-campus walkout in solidarity with students across Ontario to protest the cuts to post secondary education.
March 20 12 pm (noon) Bata Podium Add to Calendar
Peterborough Coalition Against Cuts to Education is organizing a walkout on March 20 at noon in solidarity with students across Ontario. In solidarity with students, campus unions TUFA and CUPE will be supportive of students leaving class for this event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa PSE Coalition Meeting: Feb 26</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-feb26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-feb26/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, February 26 6-8 pm 338 Somerset Street West (Side entrance) Add to Calendar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryerson University Campus Coalition Meeting: Feb 13</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, February 13 4-6pm Venn (RCC 103). Contact the coalition at Ryerson at wearethestudentsRU@gmail.com.
Coalition Meeting Invitation We Are The Students Ryerson would like to invite you and your members to attend our upcoming coalition meeting. We are a group of students and community members that are concerned about the announced changes to OSAP and post-secondary funding as well as how student fees will be collected. We know that these changes will cause uncertain work conditions for staff and faculty, less access to education and lower the value of students’ education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are the Students Ryerson: Statement on Ford&#39;s Cuts</title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-statement/</guid>
      <description>How Ryerson students will be impacted On January 17th, the provincial government announced sweeping rollbacks to the Ontario Student Assistance Program (OSAP), funding for Ontario colleges and universities and dramatically altering how student fees are administered.
The provincial government has announced a 10 per cent cut to tuition fees for domestic students across all programs, which will adversely affect each institutions’ funding. The government has also rolled back OSAP regulations to their 2016 form, which will result in a reduction in non-repayable grants and an increase in student loans and, therefore, the amount of student debt, while also proposing to remove the 6-month grace period for charging interest on student loans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/carleton-university-campus-coalition-meeting-march-14th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/carleton-university-campus-coalition-meeting-march-14th/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Carleton University&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ottawa Campuses&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-13T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;We would like to invite you and your members to attend our second coalition meeting at Carleton University. We encourage all those who are concerned and affected by the Ontario Provincial Government&amp;rsquo;s proposed cuts and changes to OSAP, post-secondary funding and changes to the collection of student fees to attend.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;Carleton Coalition&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/WeTheStudents_CarletonCoalition-01-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/carleton-university-campus-coalition-meeting-march-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/carleton-university-campus-coalition-meeting-march-7/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Carleton University&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ottawa Campuses&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Meetings&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-02-28T18:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;We would like to invite you and your members to attend our first coalition meeting at Carleton University. We encourage all those who are concerned and affected by the Ontario Provincial Government&amp;rsquo;s proposed cuts and changes to OSAP, post-secondary funding and changes to the collection of student fees to attend. &amp;quot; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;carleton-march7&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/WeTheStudents_CarletonCoalition-01.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/carleton-university-walkout-march-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/carleton-university-walkout-march-20/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Ottawa Campuses&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Carleton University&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-14T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;We encourage you to join students in opposing the government’s disastrous plan for post-secondary education and standing up for students’ right to democratic students’ unions. The involvement of your organization is meaningful to Ontario&amp;rsquo;s students and helps demonstrate broad support for fully accessible public post-secondary education.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/53489098_2030897923625247_2651014064615981056_n-3.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Carleton University Walkout - March 20&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/fanshawe-college-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/fanshawe-college-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Fanshawe College&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;London Campuses&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-14T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Join those at Fanshawe College in a walkout from 12pm-2pm at Oasis (1001 Fanshawe College Blvd.). Show your support against cuts to OSAP by demanding free education, debt forgiveness, and defending the right to organize! &amp;quot; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;Fanshawe Walkout&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/53646168_538057486685521_2133027453801594880_o.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Fanshawe College Walkout: March 20th at Noon&amp;rdquo;
+++ Join those at Fanshawe College in a walkout from 12pm-2pm at Oasis (1001 Fanshawe College Blvd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/george-brown-college-st-james-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/george-brown-college-st-james-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;George Brown College (St. James)&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-13T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;On March 20, 2019 Students of GBC will be walking out of class at 12pm/noon in demonstration of the widespread disapproval of the Ford government cuts to education. Meet in the Kings Lounge, St.James campus, 200 Kings St.E to participate in a march and get a free breakfast!&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;GBC Walkout&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/53489098_2030897923625247_2651014064615981056_n-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ocad-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ocad-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;OCAD University&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-11T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;On March 20, 2019 Students of OCAD University will be walking out of class at 12:00pm to send a clear message to the Ford Government that NO DECISIONS are to be made without the consultation of the students. We will not accept this attack on post-secondary education, OSAP and student democracy. We will walk out of 100 McCaul and organize at a near location for a student town hall where we will be discussing the detrimental reforms the government is proposing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-phoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-phoning/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Ottawa&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Events&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-05-26T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;We will be calling Power of Many supporters across the city to ask them to act and let their MPPs know that our province is not for sale to private corporations! We also need Ottawa residents to come, in large numbers, on the June 7th Day of Action events. Join us! We will train and provide a script, making it fun and easy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-pse-coalition-meeting-march-18th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ottawa-pse-coalition-meeting-march-18th/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Ottawa Campuses&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-13T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;The Ottawa PSE Coalition invites you and your members to attend our upcoming coalition meeting. We are a group of students and community members that are concerned about the announced changes to OSAP and post-secondary funding as well as how student fees will be collected. We know that these changes will cause uncertain work conditions for staff and faculty, less access to education and lower the value of students’ education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/ryerson-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Ryerson&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-13T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Join us at Ryerson for the Province-Wide Student Walk out on Wednesday, March 20th from 12pm-2pm. Meet up is at Gould and Victoria Street. Join students from across the province in a walk out on Wednesday March 20 at 12 pm to demonstrate to the Ontario government that we will not tolerate their attacks on students. There will be a number of speakers, performances and activities, oh and hot chocolate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/university-of-guelph-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/university-of-guelph-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;University of Guelph&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-13T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;The Guelph Central Students&amp;rsquo; Association will be hosting a picket and outreach day in the University Centre. Gathering at 12 noon in the UC Courtyard, we will picket the student funded and supported University Centre, reclaiming our campus back from the Ontario government! This action is in solidarity with the CUPE 1334, CUPE 3913, and CUPE 1281 members on UofG campus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/university-of-toronto-mississauga-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/university-of-toronto-mississauga-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Mississauga Campus of University of Toronto&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-13T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;UTM Joins the Province-Wide Walkout! The UTMSU calls on all students, faculty, teaching assistants, research assistants in joining students from across Ontario in walking out of class and making their voices heard. Join us for a free Brunch at the Student Centre, starting at 11:00am and walk out of classes at 12:00pm and come down to the Student Centre!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/university-of-windsor-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/university-of-windsor-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Windsor&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-14T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Join those at Windsor in a province-wide student walk out on March 20th from 12pm-2pm at the CAW Centre Courtyard. Speakers will be in attendance to address the impact of the Ford government&amp;rsquo;s disastrous cuts to post-secondary education.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;Windsor Walkout&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/53489098_2030897923625247_2651014064615981056_n-3.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;University of Windsor Walkout: March 20th at Noon&amp;rdquo;
+++ Join students from across the province in a walk out on Wednesday March 20 at 12 pm to demonstrate to the Ontario government that we will not tolerate their cuts to our education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/uoft-scarborough-coalition-meeting-march-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/uoft-scarborough-coalition-meeting-march-4/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Scarborough Campus&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Meetings&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-02-28T05:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;This meeting is for all UTSC students, staff, and faculty that want to be apart of this movement and who want to have a say in how we move forward.The evening will feature a brief overview of the changes and what they will mean for our community, but the majority of the space will be used to give community members the space to generate ideas of what our movement will look like in the coming weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/uoft-st-george-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/uoft-st-george-campus-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;University of Toronto&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-14T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;We are calling on all U of T students, staff and faculty to join us in this walk-out because enough is enough. Meet up at Sid Smith building at 10am for breakfast and banners, followed by a walkout at 12pm and a rally at 1pm at Simcoe Hall.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;StGeorge Walkout&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/53539924_2091954867506903_753915207402651648_o.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;UofT St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/western-university-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://campuscoalition.org/campus/western-university-walkout-march-20th-at-noon/</guid>
      <description>+++ campuses = [&amp;ldquo;Western University&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;London Campuses&amp;rdquo;] categories = [&amp;ldquo;Local Actions&amp;rdquo;] date = &amp;ldquo;2019-03-11T04:00:00+00:00&amp;rdquo; description = &amp;ldquo;Join the London Student Coalition and the Society of Graduate Students in a walk out on Wednesday March 20 at 12 pm on Concrete Beach in the UCC to demonstrate to the Ontario government that we will not tolerate their attacks on students.&amp;rdquo; linktitle = &amp;ldquo;Western Walkout&amp;rdquo; thumbnail = &amp;ldquo;/img/53121571_2048197881902036_1323407310843805696_o.jpg&amp;rdquo; title = &amp;ldquo;Western University Walkout: March 20th at Noon&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
